Vivienne Owusu-Ansah

www.vivienneansah.co.uk





Enthusiastic Software Developer and Digital Educator with a passion for the latest digital trends and open source technologies with over 20 years' experience in Computer Science Education.

I have good working knowledge of both front and backend technologies and operations pipelines required to plan, build and deliver software applications projects including the use of various APIs and Continuous Integration/ Continuous Delivery tools.

With excellent problem-solving skills in various technologies especially Modern JavaScript (React), I have the ability to communicate effectively whilst discussing technical problems with colleagues and clients at various levels.

I am a good listener and fast learner open to learning newer technologies in order to develop the skills required in this fast-paced technology world.

SKILLS

- Programming and Scripting JavaScript (ES6), React, HTML5, CSS3, Sass, NodeJS, Express and Python
- Configuration Management and DevOps Tools Travis-Cl, Docker, Kubernetes, Git and GitHub
- **AWS** EC2, ECS, S3, KMS, Lambda, Route53, VPC, CloudFront, Code Deploy, CloudWatch, IAM, SQS.
- Database Server MongoDB, GraphQL, SQLite, MySQL & MS SQL Server.
- Integrated Development Environment Atom, VS Code, MS Visual Studio & PyCharm.
- Operating Systems Bash, Apache Tomcat, Windows, Ubuntu (Linux) & Mac OS.
- Testing and others Jest, Slack, Google Analytics, NPM, API, JSON, YAML, GraphQL and Chrome Development Tools.















EDUCATION

January 2019	The Knowledge Academy Certified Scrum Master
November 2018	AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner
October 2018	QA London Architecting on AWS Certification Course
2003 - 2004	University of Greenwich. (PGCE with QTS)
1997 – 2000	Middlesex University BSc (Hons) Information Tech with Applied Computing
1995 – 1997	Hackney College BTEC National Diploma in Computer Studies

TECH EXPERIENCE

Junior Software Developer

April 2019 - Present Kodiri, Bermondsey, London

8 Week intensive Bootcamp

Responsibilities:

- Building a web application using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React.js and Node.js.
- Creating a Netflix based web app using react.js, JavaScript ES6+, HTML5, CSS3 and node.js, MongoDB on the backend.
- Working in teams using agile methodologies including scrum and CI tool Travis-CI.
- Pair programming on issues and task before pushing to GitHub.
- Creating Test for JavaScript and React Application using Jest.
- Collaborating using GitHub to create issues, assign to member, creating branches and pull request for other member to agree or propose changes before merging with upstream master.
- Studying JavaScript skills in class, online and on during board challenges.

- Deploying applications to Heroku and Google Cloud Platform and updating and writing necessary script in JSON and YAML.
- Researched, planned and lead a workshop on the purpose and how to use GraphQL to query a RESTful endpoint.
- Using slack to communicate and share good practice.

Software Developer

2001-2002 DRFOSTER LTD, Old Street, London

Responsibilities:

- Provided support and training to employees of DrFoster.
- Provided database-editing capabilities from within the browser for SQL server 7.0 using ASP.NET, HTML, CSS and JavaScript. Developed client/server applications using Microsoft SQL server and Visual Basic 6.
- Produced documentation, installation guide and design specification for developers.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Taught Computer Science, IT and Business Studies in various school in and around London

2014 – 2019 Rooks Heath College, Harrow

2009 – 2013 Bridge Academy, Shoreditch, London

2006 – 2009 Britton's School and Technology College, Dagenham

2004 – 2006 Marriott's School, Stevenage

Responsibilities:

- Delivering and assessing the BTEC Level 3, GCSE, A level IT, Business Studies and Computer Science qualifications to learners aged 11-19 across London and surrounding areas.
- Delivering OOP concepts and project management principles using the Agile (Scrum) methodology.
- Delivering software development training to developing applications using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, C#, python3 using the Flask Web framework and MySQL.
- Planned and delivered various topics as part the GCSE and A level Computer Science curriculum including networking, hardware architecture, data representation, software project methodologies (waterfall and agile), cyber security, relational and NoSQL database (including normalization), data structures, cloud computing, containerisation, virtualisation, testing, programming and unit testing.
- Delivering IT specific staff training and workshops in local schools in regards in teaching computer science, running coding, animation and robotics clubs.